Kyler Bomhof

kylerbomhof.com | github.com/senyc | linkedin.com/kyler-bomhof

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Software developer who is passionate about the software he writes, and systems he architects. A personal advocate for keeping code testable, and actually tested.

Kyler has professional experience with full-stack development, leading teams, and utilizing the Scrum framework.

EXPERIENCE

Haworth

Software Developer Internship

May 2023 - Aug 2023

Auto-Owners Insurance

Grand Rapids, MI

- Developed full-stack applications aimed at alleviating the burden of labor-intensive maintenance tasks performed by agents.
- Following my work's implementation, agents realized significant time savings, allowing them to allocate more time to acquiring new business.
- Adhered to the Scrum framework while collaborating with a team of business analysts, quality assurance engineers, architects, and other software developers.
- Personally responsible for front-end and back-end architectural decisions, as well as their implementation. Primarily utilized React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Jest and SQL Server.

Information Technology Internship

May 2022 - Apr 2023

Holland, MI

- Collaborated with members of the Information Security team to roll out new security software to over 7,000 devices.
- Employed tools like Microsoft Endpoint and Configuration Manager to efficiently deploy application fixes and collect various hardware and software metrics.
- Implemented solutions streamlining IT Administrators' tasks, one allowing clients to set their own desktop background, saving developer time and improving client experience.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

kylerbomhof.com July 2023 - Present

- A custom mobile-centric website that highlights my skills, experience, and projects.
- Built with cutting-edge rendering technologies, such as React server components, to decrease the initial page load and bundle size. Directly contributing to a more inclusive and improved user-experience.
- Developed using Next.js, styled with Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI, protected with reCAPTCHA. Currently hosted on Vercel.

typetest-cli June 2023 - Present

- A lightweight type speed tester for the terminal, written in Python.
- Published publicly on PyPI and easily installable using pip on any machine capable of running Python.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University

Aug 2020 - Dec 2023

Bachelor of Science - B.Sc, Computer Science

- 3.65 GPA
- It Oxygen Team Lead. Using machine learning to categorize enterprise data, allowing the client to determine manufacturing faults before they reach the market, saving thousands in potential recall costs.
- University Innovation Fellows member. Following Agile methodologies while making campus a better place.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Golang, TypeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, Lua, Bash, C, C++, Java, PowerShell

Web Development: React.js, Node.js, Rails, Express.js, Next.js, Vite, Tailwind CSS, HTML5, CSS, Material UI

CI/CD: Jenkins, Docker, GitHub Actions, Vercel, AWS

Data Management/Data Services: SQL, MySQL/MariaDB, SQL Server, REST, OpenAPI

Testing: pytest, Jest, Cypress, Selenium

System/Development Tools: Linux, Vim, tmux, Bash Scripting, AWK

Version Control/Project Management: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Scrum, Agile methodologies